<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><skill><next>&lt;p&gt;1. What _A_ would happen if the director knew you felt that way? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　A do you suppose B you suppose C will you suppose D you would suppose&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　do you supposed 常做插入语。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. _D_ the advances of science， the discomforts of old age will no doubt always be with us. [despite prep. 尽管; as for 关于，至于]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　A As for B Besides C Except D Despite&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. How close parents are to their children _B_ a strong influence on the character of the children.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　A have B has C having D to have&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　influence on 对…造成影响，很大的影响中形容词用的是strong。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4. He _A_ when the bus came to a sudden stop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　A was almost hurt B was hurt himself C was to hurt himself D was hurting himself&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　hurt oneself 自残; be to + 动词原形，将要做某事;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;5. Jean did not have time to go to the concert last night because she was busy _C_ for her examination.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　A to prepare B to be prepared C preparing D being prepared&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　be busy doing sth. 忙于做某事&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;6. Five minutes earlier， _A_ we could have caught the last train. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　A and B but C or D an ord&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;er&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　and 在这里表示一种结果，翻译成“那么(和)”。只有两种情况下and才会这样翻译：&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　 省略句 + and + 句子; 2. 祈使句 + and + 句子。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;7. Turn on the television or open a magazine and you _B_ advertisements showing happy balanced families.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　A are often seeing B will often see C often see D have often seen&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;8. I cannot give you _D_ for the type of car you sell because there is no demand for it in the market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　A an expense B a charge C a purchase D an order&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　order n. 定购，订单; purchase n. 购买。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;9. By the end of this month， we surely _C_ a satisfactory solution to the problem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　A have found B will be finding C will have found D are finding&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　如果一个句子的时间状语是由by引导的，则时态要选择完成时态。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　将来的行为在将来的某个时间之前就已完成用将来完成时。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　solution to a problem 一个问题的解决方案。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;10. Mr. Wilson said that he did not want to _A_ any further responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　A take on B get on C put up D look up&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　take on 承担; take on responsibility 承担责任。&lt;/p&gt;</next></skill>