<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><skill><next>&lt;p&gt;某些动词后要接动名词 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　某些及物动词后能用动名词而不能用不定式作宾语，其中最常用动词的有admit, avoid, appreciate, complete, consider, delay, deny, dislike, enjoy, escape, excuse, fancy, finish, forgive, involve, imagine, can’t help, mind, miss, postpone, practise, prevent, quit, resent, risk, resist, suggest等。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　She suggested spending another day in the mountain area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　There’s no way to escape doing the work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　She is considering asking her employer for a rise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　Note:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　① 在need、want、require、deserve等动词后的动名词相当于不定式的被动式&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　The clock needs/wants repairing. (=The clock needs/wants to be repaired)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　The disabled deserve respecting. (=The disabled deserve to be respected.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　② 在like、hate、prefer等动词后,如果表示一般倾向,则用动名词作宾语;如果指具体的某次发生在将来的行动，则要用不定式。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　I like reading books of this kind, but I don’t like to read that book.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　She prefers walking to cycling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　I prefer to stay at home today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　③ 在remember、forget、regret等动词后&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;,如果用动名词作宾语，则表示该宾语的动作发生在动词谓语的动作之前;如果用不定式作宾语，则表示宾语的动作发生在动词谓语的动作之后&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　I remembered locking the door. (=I remembered that I had locked the door.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　I remembered to lock the door (=I remembered that I was to lock the door.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　I regret telling you about it. (=I regret that I told you about it.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　I regret to tell you he has fallen ill. (=I regret that I am to tell you he has fallen ill.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;动名词作介词的宾语 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　动名词可作介词的宾语，与介词一起构成介词短语，在句中作定语、状语或表语。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　His dream of becoming a successful writer has come true.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　She left without saying goodbye to us. 考试用书&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　动名词作介词的宾语常用在某些词组后面。这类常用的词组主要有：be accustomed to, believe in, confess to, dream of, feel like, give up, insist on, be interested in, look forward to, object to, have an (no) objection to, pay attention to, put off, be responsible for, succeed in, be tired of, be (get) used to, worry about,等。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　He is used to living on his own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　He has made up his mind to give up smoking.&lt;/p&gt;</next></skill>