<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><skill><next>&lt;p&gt;分词: Housed in the Cultural Palace are a library, an auditorium and recreation rooms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hidden underground is a wealth of gold, silver, copper, lead and zink.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lying on the floor was a boy aged about 17.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Standing beside the table was an interpreter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;6) 句首状语若由 only + 副词,  only + 介词词组, only + 状语从句构成, 引起局部倒装:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only yesterday did he find out that his watch was missing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only through sheer luck did he manage to get some tickets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only because there were some cancelled bookings did he get some tickets in the end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;有not only开头的句子或分句, 往往引起局部倒装:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not only did he complain about the food, he also refused to pay for it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not only did the garage overcharge me, but they hadn't done a very good repair job either.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ⅷ 比较级和最高级&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;无比较级和最高级的形容词及副词: complete, perfect, utter, etc&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;比较从句&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;
as…as, almost/just/nearly as…as, not so/as …as:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'll give you as much help as we can.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I haven't made as much progress as I should.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We've produced twice as much cotton this year as we did ten years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My command of English is not half so (as) good as yours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;than, so much/a lot  more than, no more… than, not more…than, less than; more…than, less…than可表示“与其说……不如说……”:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He is more good than bad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He was less hurt than frightened.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The present crisis in capitalist countries is much more a political than an economic crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“no + 形容词或副词比较级 + than”所表示的可以是该形容词或副词的相反的含义:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;no rich than = as poor as&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;no bigger than = as small as&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;no later than = as early as&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;John is no better than Tom.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have taken no more than six courses this semester.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;the more… the mor&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;e (越是……就越……)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Actually, the busier he is, the happier he feels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The more they talked, the more encouraged they felt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;more of a, as much of a, less of a, etc: 当as much of a…as, more/less of a …than等结构与单数可数名词搭配时, 名词只能置于比较结构中间.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He is more of a sportsman than his brother.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ⅸ 名词性从句: 名词性从句包括主语从句, 宾语从句, 表语从句, 同位语从句。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;主语从句有三类:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;由what等代词引导的主语从句: what表示“所……的(东西)”, 在结构上等于一个名词加一个定语从句; whatever表示“所……的一切”; whoever表示“一切……的人”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What you need is more practice&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is hard is to do good all one’s life and never do anything bad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whatever was said here must be kept secret.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whatever I have is at your service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whoever comes will be welcome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whoever fails to see this will make a big blunder.&lt;/p&gt;</next></skill>