<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><skill><next>&lt;p&gt;全部倒装和部分倒装: 如果谓语在主语前面, 就是倒装语序. 倒装语序又分为全部倒装和部分倒装. 在全部倒装的句子中, 整个谓语都放在主语的前面:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are some registered letters for you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In came a man with a white beard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;       在部分倒装的句子中只是谓语中的一部分(如助动词, 情态动词, 或系动词be等)放在主语前面, 其余部分仍在主语后面:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under no circumstances must a soldier leave his post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I couldn't answer the question. Nor could anyone else in our class.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only in this way is it possible to accomplish the above-mentioned glorious task.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      以neither, nor, so等开始的句子: 由so引起的表示前面所说情况也适用于另一人(或东西)的句子(肯定句), 由neither, nor引起的表示前面所说情况也适用于另一人(或东西)的句子(否定句), 助动词或be置于主语前.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We must start for the work-site now". " So must we."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am quite willing to help and so are the others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He didn't drop any hint. Nor (Neither) did his secretary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I won't do such a thing.""Nor (Neither) will I."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;     如果一个句子只是重复前面一句话的意思, 尽管是用so开头, 语序也不要颠倒.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"It was cold yesterday." "So it was."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;|"Tomorrow will be Monday.""So it will."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      当句首状语为 never, little, not only, not until, hardly, scarcely等否定词或有否定意义的词语时, 一般引起部分倒装.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No longer are they staying with us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No sooner had he arrived there than he fell ill.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under no circumstances could I agree to such a principle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      表示位置或方向的副词提前, 谓语动词为 go, come等表示位置转移的动作动词而主语又较长时, 通常用全部倒装:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was a sudden gust of wind and away went his hat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The door burst open and I rushed the crowd.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There comes the bus!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now comes your turn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 如果主语是代词, 仍用正常语序:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There comes your turn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;有here引起, 谓语为be的句子, 也要倒装:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is China's largest tropical forest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are some picture-books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;如果主语是代词, 仍用正常语序:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here we are. This is the new railway station.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Give me som&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;e paper.""Here you are."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;表语和系动词提前:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;介词短语: On the other side was northern Xinjiang.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Near the southern end of the village was a large pear orchard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;形容词: Very important in the farmer's life is the radio weather report.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Worst of all were the humiliations he suffered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;副词: Below is a restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Southwest of the reservoir were 2,000 acres of sandy wasteland.&lt;/p&gt;</next></skill>