<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><skill><next>&lt;p&gt;在介词后只能用which, 在口语中一般都把介词放到从句后部去, 这时可以用that, 但省略的时候更多一些:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tool with which he is working is called a wrench.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tool (that) he is working with is called a wrench.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the question about which we've had so much discussion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the question (that) we've had so much discussion about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      定语从句一般是修饰名词或代词的, 但间或也可以修饰整个句子a), 或是句子的一部分 b), 引导词用which:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They have invited me to visit their country, which is very kind of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The activity was postponed, which was exactly what we wanted&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When deeply absorbed in work, which he often was, he would forget all about eating and sleeping.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She was very patient towards the children, which her husband seldom was.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      whose: 在表示“......的”这个概念时, 可用所有格 whose; whose 用于指物, 有时可与of which交替使用, 通常的词序是 名词词组 + of which:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is there anyone &lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;in your class whose family is in the northeast?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We had a meeting whose purpose was completely unclear. (…the purpose of which was…)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He's written a book the name of which I’ve completely forgotten. (…whose name I've…)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;       of which前的名词词组也可以由some, any, none, all, both, several, enough, many, most, few以及基数词担任; 这些词也能用在 of whom之前.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The buses, most of which were already full, were surrounded by an angry crowd.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's a family of eight children, all of whom are studying music.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      关系副词 when, where, why: 它们的含义相当于 at which, in which, for which, 因此它们之间有交替使用的可能.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The day when he was born…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;on which he was born…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;which he was born on…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The office where he works…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;at which he works…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;which he works at…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;有时可用that替代关系副词, 在口语中that 可省略.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every time (that) the telephone rings, he gets nervous.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was the first ti&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;me I had serious trouble with my boss.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you know anywhere (that) I can get a drink?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the place (where) we met yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That is the reason (why) he did it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;在the way 后也可用that 替代in which, 在口语中that也可省略.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the way (that/in which) he did it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That's the way I look at it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;如果定语从句中谓语为 there is, 作主语的关系代词也常可省掉:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I must make full use of the time there is left to me and do as much as I can for the people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the fastest train (that) there is to Nanjing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      定语从句的简化: 定语从句与不定式结构, -ing分词结构, -ed分词结构以及无动词分句等有着转换关系.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He was the only one to realize the danger (= who realized the danger).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The woman driving the car (= who was driving the car) indicated that she was going to turn left.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The man injured by the bullet (= who was injured by the bullet) was taken to hospital.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All the women present (= who were present) looked up in alarm.&lt;/p&gt;</next></skill>