<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><skill><next>&lt;p&gt;并列连词&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;表示意义的引申: and, both…and, not only…but(also), as well as, and …as well, neither…nor&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;表示选择: or, either…or&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;表示转折: but, while, whereas, yet, however/nevertheless(也可认为是副词)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;表示因果: for, so, therefore, hence&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;从属连词&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;表示时间: when, while, as, after, before, since, until(till), as soon as, once&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;表示原因: because, as, since, now that, seeing that&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;表示条件: if, unless, in case, provided(that), suppose, as long as, on condition (that),&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;表示其他关系: (al)though, than, as/so…as, lest, in order that, so…that&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ⅵ 定语从句&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      限制和非限制性定语从句: 限制性定语从句是名词词组不可缺少的一个组成部分, 去掉了会造成病句或意义不明确; 非限制性定语从句属于补充说明性质, 去掉了不会影响主要意义, 通常用逗号与它的先行词分开.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The boys who wanted to play football were disappointed when it rained.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The boys, who wanted to play football, were disappointed when it rai&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;ned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      如果定语从句的先行词是专有名词, 或是带有形容词性物主代词(my, his, etc)或形容词性指示代词(this, that, etc)作限定词, 其后的定语从句通常都是非限制性的:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mary Smith, who is in the corner, wants to meet you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her mother, who had long suffered form arthritis, died last night.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All these books, which have been donated by visiting professors, are to be used by the postgraduates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      在非限制性定语从句中只能用who/whom指人, 用which指物,通常不用that替代.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My father, who had been on a visit to America, returned yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All the books, which had pictures in them, were sent to the little girl.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;定语从句的引导词&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      that, who, whom: 非限制性定语从句, 如果修饰人, 一般用who, 有时用that (作主语时用who较多). 如果关系代词在从句中作宾语, 就应当用宾格 whom 或that, 但在大多数情况下都可以省略掉, 在口语中可用who代替whom.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is the man (whom) you've been looking for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He is a man (that) you can safely depend on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The people (who/that) you were talking to were Sw&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;edes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are some people here who I want you to meet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;但在介词后只能用whom:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the man to whom I referred.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;但在口语中一般都把介词放到句子后面去, 这时可用that, 但省略时更多一些.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you met the person about whom he was speaking?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you met the person (that) he was speaking about&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The girl to whom I spoke is my cousin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The girl (who/that) I spoke to is my cousin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      限制性定语从句如果修饰“物”, 用关系代词that的时候较多, 也有时用which.. 当这个代词在从句中是用作宾语时, 在绝大多数情况下都是省略的, 特别是口语中(尤其是当被修饰的词是all, everything等词时):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you everything you need?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Is there) anything I can do for you?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All you have to do is to press the button&lt;/p&gt;</next></skill>