<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><skill><next>&lt;p&gt;that从居中:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;wish, would rather (sooner), had better:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wish I were as strong as you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wish I had paid more attention to our pronunciation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wish I remembered the address.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would rather they came tomorrow (you had gone there too).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had rather (that) you told him than I did.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      suggest, order, demand, propose, command, request, desire, insist 等动词后的宾语从句:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The commander ordered that all civilians (should) be evacuated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He asked that he be given an opportunity to try.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She urged that he write and accept the post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      it is desired, it is suggested, it is requested, it was ordered, it was proposed, it is necessary, it is important, it has been decided 等结构后的主语从句中.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was arranged that they leave the following week&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It will be better that we meet some other time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      suggestion, motion, proposal, ord&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;er, recommendations, plan, idea等后面的表语从句和同位语从句:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His sole requirement is (was) that thy system be adjusted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;     在某些句型中&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;it is time that&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is time that we went (或should go) to bed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is high time we (should) put an end to this controversy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      as if (though) 引起的从句:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They talked (are talking) as if they had been friends for years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It seems as if it was (were) spring today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He acts (acted) as if (though) he were (was) an expert.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      以lest, for fear that 和 in case 引起的从句(这时谓语多用 should +动词原形):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He took his raincoat with him lest it should rain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He put his coat over the child for fear that (或lest) he should catch cold.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'll keep a seat for you in case you should need it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      以whatever, whoever, no matter what这类代词或词组引起的从句(这时, 谓语多用may加动词原形构成):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whatever defects he may have, he is an honest man.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Come what may, we will go ahead.  不管发生什么情况, 我们都要干下去.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I accept that he is old and frail; be that as it may, he's still a good politician.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;我承认他年老体衰, 然而尽管如&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;此, 它仍是优秀的政治家.&lt;/p&gt;</next></skill>