<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><skill><next>&lt;p&gt;来自不及物动词的过去分词很少能单独用作前置修饰语, 能作这样用的仅限于下面几个词, 仅表示完成意义, 不表示被动意义.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;the risen sun, fallen leaves, faded /withered flowers, returned students, retired workers, departed friends, escaped prisoners, the vanished jewels, newly-arrived visitors&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      用作后置修饰语的过去分词一般都带有修饰语或其他成分, 在意义上相当于关系分句.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of the people invited to the reception were old friends.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;句法作用&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;     作定语: distinguished guest 贵宾, unknown heroes 无名英雄, armed forces武装部队, canned food罐头食品, boiled water开水, steamed bread馒头, stricken area灾区分词还可构成合成词作定语: simply-furnished room陈设简单的房间, clear-cut answer明确的答复, highly-developed industry高度发展的工业, heartfelt thanks衷心的感谢, hand-made goods手工制品, man-made satellite人造卫星&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;作补足语: 可以带过去分词作宾语补足语的动词有:see, hear, feel, find, think等表示感觉和心理状态的动词.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I saw the students assembled in the hall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We found her greatly changed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;make, get, have, keep等表示”致使”意义的动词:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have my hair cut every ten days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She got her bad tooth pulled out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please keep us informed of the latest developments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;like, want, wish, &lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;order等表示希望, 要求, 命令等意义的动词:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't want any of you (to be) involved in the scandal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He won't like such questions (to be) discussed at the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      过去分词短语常用作状语, 修饰谓语, 很多都说明动作发生的背景或情况.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guided by these principles, they went on with the work,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Delighted with her work, they made her the general manager.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      过去分词短语也可作状语表示原因, 相当于一个表示原因的状语从句.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Influenced by his example, they performed countless good deeds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      有时也可说明动作发生的时间, 相当于一个表示时间的状语从句.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This method, tried in areas near Shanghai, resulted in a marked rise in total production.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      间或也可表示一个假设的情况, 相当于一个条件从句.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given closer analysis, we can see this is totally wrong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      偶尔也可用来代替一个“让步”状语从句.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Picked 20 years a year, it grows tired only after 40 or 50 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      独立结构: 在用分词短语作状语时, 它逻辑上的主语一般必须与句子的主语一.致. 但有时它也可以有自己独立的逻辑上的主语, 这种结构称为独立结构, 一般表示一种伴随的动作或情况.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He rushed into the room, his face covered with sweat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;有时可以表示时间:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Late &lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;that autumn, his work finished, he prepared to return to his institute.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;表示原因:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her eyes dimmed with tears, she did not see him enter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;条件:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All things considered, her paper is of greater value than yours.&lt;/p&gt;</next></skill>