<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><skill><next>&lt;p&gt;现在分词短语有时可用作时间状语, 相当于when引起的从句:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      Seeing those pictures, he couldn't help thinking of those memorable days they spent together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;       如果两个动作是完全同时发生的, 多用when 或while加分词这种结构.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be careful when crossing the street.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When leaving the airport, they waved again and again to us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She got to know them while attending a conference in Beijing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      前面带有代词或名词的动名词结构: 一个动名词前面可以加一个物主代词(或名词的所有格结构), 来表示这个动名词逻辑上的主语.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Their coming to help was a great encouragement to us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our sole worry is your relying too much on yourself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you mind my reading your paper?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They insisted on my staying there for supper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      如果不是在句子开头, 这个结构常常可以用名词的普通格(或人称代词宾格), 这比用所有格更自然一些.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't mind him going.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She hates people losing their temper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      只能用动名词作宾语的动词: suggest, finish, avoid, stop, can't help, mind, admit, enjoy, leave off, require, pos&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;tpone, put off, delay, practise, fancy, excuse, pardon, advise, consider, deny, endure, escape, miss&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      既可用动名词, 也可用不定式作宾语的动词: love, like, hate, dislike, begin, start, continue, intend, attempt, can’t bear, propose, want, need, remember, forget, regret, neglect, try, deserve, can’t afford等.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      有时两种结构之间意义差别不大, 有时却有不同的意思. 在remember, regret, want, try等词后差别是比较明显的.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I remember seeing her once somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I must remember to take my notebooks with me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I regret not having accepted your advice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I regret to say I haven't given you enough help.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She doesn't want (need) to come.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The house wants (needs) cleaning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We must try to get everything done in time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let's try doing the work some other way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      悬垂修饰: 分词作状语时, 表示的必须是主语的一个动作或状态.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Walking through the park, we saw a lot of flowers. (walking是we的动作, 正确)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Walking through the park, the flowers looked very beautiful. (错误)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Standing on the tower, we could see the whole city. (正确)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Standing on the tower, the whol&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;e village could be seen. (错误)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;分词&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      意义: 过去分词通常来自及物动词, 带有被动意义和完成意义; 而现在分词有的来自及物动词, 有的来自不及物动词, 通常带有主动意义和未完成意义.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;frozen food   a freezing wind&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;a bored traveller  a boring journey&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;a lost cause   a losing battle&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;a conquered army  a conquering army&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;a finished article  the last finishing touch&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;the spoken word  a speaking bird&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;a closed shop  the closing hour&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;a recorded talk  a recording machine&lt;/p&gt;</next></skill>