<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><skill><next>&lt;p&gt;too…to 结构通常表示否定意义:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She was too young to understand all that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      enough…to结构则表示肯定意义:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She was not old enough to understand all that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      not too, but too, all too, only too等和不定式连用时,不定式一般不表示否定意义:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He's only too pleased to help her.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      so…as (to)这种结构也可用不定式作状语:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be so kind as to drop in some time when you are free.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      如果要说明不定式表示的动作是谁做的, 可以在不定式前加一个for引起的短语:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is not hard for one to do a bit of good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is a great honour for us to be present at this rally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      在以某些形容词(如 kind, good, nice, wise, unwise, clever, silly, wrong, right, foolish, stupid, careless, considerate, rude, naughty, impolite等)作表语时, 不定式前可加一个of引起的短语, 来说明不定式指的是谁的情况:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's kind of you to think so much of us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(It is) Awfully go&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;od of you to come and meet us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's very nice of you to be so considerate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's unwise of them to turn down the proposal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;V+ing形式(现在分词及动名词)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;形式&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      完成式: 如果要表示动名词代表的动作在谓语所表示的动作之前发生, 通常用动名词的完成形式.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He didn't mention having met me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I regret not having taken her advice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      在某些动词后(或成语中), 常用(或可以用)动名词的一般形式, 尽管动作是在谓语所表示的动作之前发生的.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Excuse me for coming late.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't remember ever seeing him anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      现在分词的完成式主要用在状语中, 表示这动作在谓语所表示的动作之前发生.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having been there many times, he offered to be our guide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having found the cause, they were able to propose a remedy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      另外, 独立结构也可用现在分词的完成形式.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The guests having left, they resumed their discussion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The children, having eating their fill, were allowed to leave the table.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      被动式: 当一个动名词逻辑上的主语所表示的是这动作的对象时, 动名词一般要用被动形式.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His being neglected &lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;by the host added to his uneasiness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He couldn't bear being made fun of like that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      但要注意, 在want, need, deserve, require 等动词后, 尽管表示的是被动的意思, 却用动名词的主动形式.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My pen needs filling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The point deserves mentioning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This problem requires studying with great care.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;在worth这个形容词后情形也是这样.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her method is worth trying.&lt;/p&gt;</next></skill>