<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><skill><next>&lt;p&gt;被动式: 当不定式的逻辑上的主语是不定式所表示的动作的承受者时, 不定式一般要用被动形式.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    It is an honour for me to be asked to speak here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    She hated to be flattered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    He wanted the letter to be typed at once.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    This is bound to be found out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    There are a lot of things to be done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    She was too young to be assigned such work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    功用: 不定式可以作主语 (a), 宾语 (b), 表语 (c), 定语 (d) 或是状语 (e).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    a. To scold her would not be just.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    b. We are planning to build a reservoir here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    c. One of our main tasks now is to mechanize agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    d. Do you have anything to declare?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    e. We have come to learn from you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    不带to 的不定式:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    在“动词+ 宾语+不定式”结构中, 如果动词是表示感觉意义的see, hear, watch, smell, feel, notice等, 或是表示“致使”意义的 have, make, let等, 其后的不定式结构不带to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    John made her tell him everything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    这类结构转换为被动语态时, 后面的不带to 的不定式一般还原为带to 的不定式.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    She was made to tell him everything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    在 had better, had best, would rather, would sooner, would just as soon, might (just) as well, cannot but 等搭配之后, 动词不定式也不带to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    I'd rather not have eggs and bacon for breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    They cannot but accept his term.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    在make do, make believe, let drop, let fall, let fly, let slip, let drive, let go of, let there be, hear say, hear tell, leave go of等固定搭配中, 用不带to的动词不定式.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    John let fly a torrent of abuse at me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    I've heard tell of him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    在动词help(或help +宾语)之后可用不带to的不定式, 也可用带to的不定式.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    Can I help (to) lift this heavy box?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    在介词except, but 之后, 如果其前有动词do的某种形式, 不定式一般不带to, 反之带to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    There is nothing to do except wait till it stops raining.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    Smith will do anything but work on a farm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    There's no choice but to wait till it stops raining.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    连词 rather than, sooner than 置于句首时, 其后的不定式不带to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    Rather than push the book back as he wanted to do, he forced himself to pick it up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    出现在句中其他位置时, 其后的不定式有时带to, 有时不带to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    He decided to write rather than telephone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    The manager believes it is important to invest in new machinery rather than to increase wages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    用作补语的动词不定式, 如果主语是由“all + 关系分句”，“thing +关系分句”，“what分句”或“thing +不定式结构”等构成，并带有do的某种形式，这时，作为主语补语的不定式可以省to，也可以不省.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    What he will do is (to) spoil the whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    All you do now is complete the form&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    The only thing I can do now is go on by myself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    The thing to do now is clear up this mess.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;
    The least I can do is drive everybody else closer to the issue.&lt;/p&gt;</next></skill>