<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><skill><next>&lt;p&gt;省略&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    在以as, than, when, if, unless等引导的从句中的省略: 在有些状语从句中,如果谓语包含有动词be,主语又和主句的主语一致a),或者主语是it b),就常常可以把从句中的主语和谓语的一部分(特别是动词be)省略掉.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    Look out for cars when crossing the street.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    When taken according to the directions, the drug has no side effects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    While there he joined in voluntary labour on a project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    Although not yet six months old, she was able to walk without support.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    If not well managed, irrigation can be harmful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    Though reduced in numbers, they gained in fighting capacity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    This viewpoint, however understandable, is wrong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    Enemies, once discovered, were tightly encircled and completely wiped out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    She hurriedly left the room as though/if angry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    She worked extremely hard though still rather poor in health.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    Fill in the application as instructed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    Whenever known, such facts should be reported.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    The documents will be returned as soon as signed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    He said that no acrobat could ever perform those daring feats unless trained very young.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    Once having made a promise, you should keep it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    If necessary I’ll have the letter duplicated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    Fill in the blanks with articles where(ver) necessary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    If possible, I should like to have two copies of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    As scheduled, they met on January 20 at the Chinese Embassy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;     在以than a) 或 as b) 引起的从句中,常会有一些成分省略.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    He told me not to use more material than (it is) necessary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    We should think more of the collective than of ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    They worked with as much enthusiasm as young people (did).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    He is now a vice-manager, but still often works in the kitchen as before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    Their training is free, as is all education.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    We will, as always, stand on your side.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;     错误的省略&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    His life is as fully committed to books as anyone I know.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    While standing there in her nightgown, two bullets struck the wall beside her.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    一致&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    如果主语是单数,尽管后面跟有with, together with, as well as, as much as, no less than, more than等引导的短语,谓语动词仍旧用单数形式.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    Terry, along with her friend, goes skating every Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    An expert, together with some assistants, was sent to&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt; help in this work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    The captain, as well as the coaches, was disappointed in the team.&lt;/p&gt;</next></skill>