<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><skill><next>&lt;p&gt;很多同学都说考英语六级的时候，阅读理解总是时间不够用，往往都要收卷了，还有一两篇没有做，在种紧急状况下，该如何提高剩下文章的命中率呢？这里我们介绍一些临门一脚的做题窍门。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　 (一)针对主旨大意题只读段首、段尾句。一般来说，一篇文章的中心思想或某一段主题思想往往通过段首、段尾句表达出来。考生迅速找到了这些主题句，也能答题。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例(1) The author writes this passage to _____ 。(1995年6月六级题30)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　A. discuss the negative aspect of being attractive。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　B. give advice to job-seekers who are attractive&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　C. demand equal rights for woman&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　D. emphasize the importance of appearance&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　(分析：考生若没有时间看整个文章，但只要看到第一段最后一句话：But in the executive circle, beauty can become a liability. 第二段第一句话：While attractiveness is a positive factor for a man on his way up the executive ladder, it is harmful to a woman. 考生亦能选出正确答案项A。)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例(2) The main idea of this passage is that _____ 。(1991年6月六级题40)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　A. better use of greenspace facilities should be made so as to improve the quality of our life&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　B. attention must be directed to the improvement of recreative possibilities。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　C. the urban environment is providing more recreation activities than it did many years ago.??&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;
　　D. priority must be given to the development of obligatory activities。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　(分析：此题主要考某一段的中心意思。考生苦看到了该段第一句话：Greenspace facilities are contributing to an important extent to the quality of the urban environment. 即使没有通读全段，考生也应能选出A项为正确答案。)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　 (二)若针对举例子、引用名人言论、特殊符号(如冒号、引号、破折号)后内容出题，考生可只读例子、名人言话、符号前后句内容，然后符号题。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例(1) Tish Sommers argues that _____ . (1994上1月六级题28)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　A. older women find it hard to escape poverty。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　B. older women usually perform better in their jobs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　C. the major cause of the poverty of older women is sexism&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　D. more people have come to believe in sexism and ageism。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　(分析：考生一看到题干，迅速到文章中找到Tish Sommers 的位置，人名开头字母大写，容易找到，且有双引号引用了她的原话："When sexism meets ageism, poverty is no longer in the doorstep it moves in"。考生只要看看新引用的话及前后句内容，就能选出正确答案A项。)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例(2) According to Dr. David, Americans _____ . (1993年6月六级题32)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　A. are ideally vigorous even under the pressure of life&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　B. often neglect the consequences of sleep deficit&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　C. do not know how to relax themselves properly&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　D.&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt; can get by on 6.5 hours of sleep。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　(分析：考生一看到此人名字，迅速从课文中找到，然后细读他所说的话："people cheat on their sleep, and they don't even realize they're doing it,"says Dr. David. "They think they're key because they can get by on 6.5 hours, when they really need 7.5, eight or even more to feel ideally vigorous."只要理解了这些话，考生应能选出B项。)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(三)如果题目只是针对某一段内容而提问，考生可只看该段内容即可答题，而不必等把文章全看完才做，以防到时要交卷，而能做出的题因时间不足而瞎猜。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例(1) In the first paragraph, the author gives the definitions of some terms in order to _____ 。(1996年1月六级题26) (建议：考生看完第一段就做此题，不必看后面内容)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例(2) From the third paragraph, we can leard that _____ 。(建议：考生只看第三段，然后迅速答题。)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　(四)针对词汇题，考生可只看词汇所在句和前后句内容即可答题，因为对单词字义的揣测，一般只通过单词所在句或前后句内容就能猜出。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例(1) The word "dubious"(Line. 2)most probably means _____ 。(1990年1月六级题33)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　A.valuable B. useful C. doubtful D. helpful&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　(分析：对"dubious"一词词义的揣测，可根据该单词所在句和其前面一句话即可猜出。Yet you will find little if anything written on what it is to be an employee. You can find a great deal of very dubious advice on how to get a job or how to get a promotion. 从这两句可猜出dubious是含有贬义、否定语气的，故选C。)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例(2) The word "hassles" in the passage (Line 4) probably means _____ 。(1993年6月六级题24)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　A. agreement&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;s B. disadvantages C. worries D. quarrels&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　(分析：判断"hassles"意思，可从该词所在句前后句判断出。But sharing the family home requires adjustments for all. There are the hassles over bathrooms, telephones and privacy. Some families, however, manage the delicate balancing act. But for others, it proves too difficult. 从前后句意思及介词over, 考生可猜出"hassles"就是quarrels。)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;        除了掌握这些技巧，考生还需注意以下两点 ：&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;       一、考前多做准备。考前应多做真题，严格按照考试时间、顺序训练，制定好适合自己的应试策略，确保尽量不出现时间不够用的情况。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;       二、及时调整心态。即使时间不够用，也不要着急，因为大多数同学在六级考试的时候都有时间不够用之感，要有“我做不完，别人也做不完”的阿Q精神。而且我们做了这么多的训练，掌握了这么多的技巧，我们有足够的底气来相信——即使剩下的时间少，我们也依然能把题做对。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;      最后，祝各位考生在六级考试中取得良好的成绩！&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;（文都四六级考试研究中心）&lt;/p&gt;</next></skill>