<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><skill><next>&lt;p&gt;（九）“many+单数名词”等结构的主谓一致&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　主语为many a/more than one/every/each+单数名词或one of/every one of/either of/neither of/each of+复数名词时，谓语动词用单数形式。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： Caught in the web of its own time and place， each generation of historians determines anew what is significant for it in the past. (选自1999年Part IV)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是复合句，主干部分是each generation of historians determines anew...，what is significant for it in the past是determines的宾语从句，过去分词caught in the web of...作主语补足语。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 每一代史学家在重新确定那些对他们具有重大意义的史实时，都会受到自身时空的局限。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;例句： Each of these social sciences has a subfield or specialization which lies particularly close to anthropology. （选自2003年Part B）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是复合句，which lies...是修饰subfield or specialization的定语从句。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 每一门社会学科目都有一个分支或专业特别接近人类学。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　（十）“each+单数名词”等结构的主谓一致&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　在each/every+单数名词+and+ each/every+单数名词这一结构作主语时，谓语动词用单数形式。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： Every boy and every girl has a right to be educated in our country， whether his/her family is rich or poor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是并列句，whether his family is rich or poor这一分句表示让步。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;： 在我国，无论男孩女孩都有权利接受教育，不管家庭贫穷与否。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　（十一）“a lot of+不可数名词（复数名词）”等结构的主谓一致&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　a lot of/lots of/heaps of/a load of/loads of/the rest/the last/half of/part of/enough of/a great （good) deal of+ 不可数名词 + 单数谓语动词&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　复数名词 + 复数谓语动词&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： A great deal of attention is being paid today to the socalled digital divide—the division of the world into the info (information) rich and the info poor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　（选自2001年Text 2）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是简单句，破折号后内容是对其前内容的进一步解释说明。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 今天，人们十分关注所谓的信息差异问题——也就是把世界上的国家分成信息资源丰富国和信息资源贫乏国。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　（十二）and或both...and并列结构&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　该结构作主语时，谓语动词用复数形式，但由and连接的两名词指同一人或同一物体时，谓语动词用单数形式。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： The weeds and tall grass in that yard make the house look as if it had been vacant for quite some time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是复合句，其中as if后引导的方式状语从句作look的宾语。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 院子里的杂草和长得很高的青草使这房子看起来好像相当长一段时间没住过人似的。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： The capacity and efficiency with which your body can perform depends on the degree of development of both your muscular and organic power through regular exercise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是复合句，主干部分为the capacity and efficiency depends on the degree of development， wi&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;th which your body can perform是修饰the capacity and efficiency的定语从句，介词短语of both your muscular and...修饰development。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 你的身体所能表现出来的能力和效能取决于你的肌肉和有机能量通过日常锻炼而达到的程度。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　（十三）数词与表示时间、金钱、度量衡、温度等名词&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　这类名词作主语表示一定量或总量时，谓语动词用单数形式。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： Two years seems a long time for a patient who has to lie in bed， and do nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是复合句， who has to lie in bed， and do nothing是修饰a patient的定语从句。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 对于一个不得不躺在床上并且无事可做的病人来说，两年时间的确很漫长。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： Sixty kilograms is a heavy weight for her， so she will try her best to make regular exercises for losing the weight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是并列句。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 60公斤对她来说的确是太重了，于是她将尽最大努力通过日常锻炼来减肥。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;（十四）分数或百分比+ of+单数名词+单数动词&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　复数名词+复数动词&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： By the third generation， one third of Hispanic women are married to nonHispanics， and 41 percent of AsianAmerican women are married to nonAsians.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　（选自2006年Text 1）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是由and连接的并列句。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 到了第三代，讲西班牙语的移民中，有1/3的妇女嫁给了不讲西班牙语的美国人。41%的亚洲移民妇女嫁给了不是来自亚洲的美国人。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： But the human mind&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt; can glimpse a rapidly changing scene and immediately disregard the 98 percent that is irrelevant， instantaneously focusing on the monkey at the side of a winding forest road or the single suspicious face in a big crowd.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　（选自2002年Text 2）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是复合句，主干部分是the human mind can glimpse...and disregard the 98 percent，分词短语focusing on在句中作伴随状语。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 但是人类的头脑能在一瞥之下发现一个迅速改变的场景，随即忽略抛弃其中98%的无关信息，瞬间定位在蜿蜒的林间小路旁的那只猴子或人群中那张可疑的面孔上。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： More than one third of the Chinese in the United States live in California， predominately in San Francisco．&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是简单句。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 在美国，1/3的华人居住在加利福尼亚州，主要集中在旧金山市。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;（十五）集体名词&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　army， board， family， committee， couple， crowd， crew， Jury， staff， team， public， government， community， panel（陪审团、专家小组），thinktank（智囊团）作主语，指整体时谓语动词用单数，指集体各成员时，谓语动词用复数。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： The panel has not yet reached an agreement on a crucial question， however， whether to recommend legislation that would make it a crime for private funding to be used for human cloning. （选自1999年Text 4）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是复合句，其中that would make it...是一定语从句修饰legislation， whether to recommend...其完整形式为whether they are to recommend，本句的主干为The panel has not yet reached an agreement。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;　译文： 不过，专家小组对是否建议将私人资金用于克隆人类的行为视为犯罪这一问题尚未达成一致意见。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： With economic growth has come centralization， fully 76 percent of Japans 119 million citizens live in cities where community and the extended family have been abandoned in favor of isolated， twogeneration household. （选自2000年Text 4）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 本句是复合句，主干部分为fully 76 percent of Japans 119 million citizens live in cities，介词with接一从句在句中作状语表示原因，where community and the extended family have been abandoned是修饰cities的定语从句。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 由于经济的发展逐渐集中化，在日本的1.19亿国民中，76%的人居住在城市，社区和大家庭逐渐被独立的、两代人组成的小家庭所取代。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　（十六）单复数同形的名词作主语&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　sheep， deer， fish， aircraft， hovercraft， crossroads， headquarters， means， series， works， species等作主语时，根据句中出现的限定词（如：a/an， a few， several， this/that， these/those， every， each， all等）或代词确定谓语动词的单复数。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： Furthermore， in the early days of longline fishing， a lot of fish were lost to sharks after they had been hooked. （选自2006年Text 3）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是复合句，after they had been hooked是时间状语从句。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 另外，早期用多钩长线钓鱼，很多被钩过的鱼只能葬身鲨鱼腹中。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： In Europe， where forestry is ecologically more advanced， the noncommercial tree species are recognized as members of th&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;e native forest community， to be preserved as such， within reason. (2010年第49题)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是复合句，句子的主体是the noncommercial tree species are recognized as members of the native forest community，where引导的定语从句修饰Europe，不定式to be preserved修饰noncommercial tree species， within reason意为“合情合理的；理智的”。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 欧洲的林业从生态上讲较为先进，它把没有成为商业化对象的树种视为原始森林群落的一部分而适当地加以保护。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　（十七）the number of+复数可数名词谓语动词用单数；主语部分为a number of+复数可数名词，谓语动词用复数&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： When a number of people cluster together in a conversation knot， each individual expresses his position in the group by where he stands.（1997年第40题）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是复合句，主句部分为each individual expresses his position in the group， by...在句中作状语，修饰expresses，where he stands作介词by的宾语从句。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 许多人聚在一起谈话时，小组中的每个人都从自己的角度表达了个人立场。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： Although the figure may vary， analysts do agree on another matter： that the number of the homeless is increasing， one of the federal governments studies predicts that the number of the homeless will reach nearly 19 million by the end of this decade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　（选自2006年Use of English）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是复合句，冒号前是让步状语从句，冒号后内容是对其前内容的进一步解释，that the number of the homeless will...是predicts的宾语。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 虽然各种估计的数量不一致，但分析&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;家们却在一件事上达成了一致，即无家可归的人口数量在上升。联邦政府的一项研究预测，在这个十年结束之前，无家可归者的数量将接近1 900万。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　——选自《考研英语语法重难点精解（2013）》 中国人民大学出版社&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　第二章 句子　&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　第七节 主谓一致&lt;/p&gt;</next></skill>