<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><skill><next>&lt;p&gt;一.在谓语动词前加助动词do， did， does强调该谓语动词，构成强调句&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： The president of the National Academy， Bruce Alberts， added this key point in the preface to the panels report “Science never has all the answers. But science does provide us with the best available guide to the future， and it is critical that our nation and the world base important policies on the best judgments that science can provide concerning the future consequences of present actions. ”（选自2005年Text 2）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 引号内由两个句子组成， but前一分句是一个简单句，后一分句为两个并列句，其中第一个分句中的does表强调，第二个并列句为一复合句，真正的主语为that our nation and the world base important policies on...， it为形式主语，定语从句that science can provide concerning the future...修饰judgment。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 国家科学院院长布鲁斯·艾伯茨在会议报告的前言中补充和强调了这一点，即科学解答不了所有的问题，但科学的确能给我们提供将来可行的最好的指导，关键是我们国家和其他各国在做重要决策时应该以科学能够提供给我们的、对于人类现在的行为对未来影响的最好的判断作为依据。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　二.强调句中谓语以外的其他成分时用强调句型（见词类中it用法）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： Often its the delivery that causes the audience to smile， so speak slowly and remember that a raised eyebrow or an unbelieving look may help to show that you are making a lighthearted remark. （选自2002年Text 1）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是复合句，主句its the delivery that causes the audience to smile是一个强调句，that a raised eyebrow or an unbelieving look和that you are making a light hearted remark分别作remember以及show的宾语， lighthearted是一个复合形容词修饰remark。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 这是一种经常使听众发笑的讲述方法，所以&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;，讲得慢一些，记住扬一扬眉，或一副不相信的表情可以有助于表现出你正在做一场轻松愉快的评论。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： It is the playgoers， the RSC(Royal Shakespeare Company) contends， who bring in much of the towns revenue because they spend the night(some of them four or five nights) pouring cash into the hotels and restaurants.（选自2006年Text 2）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是复合句，the RSC contends是插入语，it is the playgoers who bring in much of the towns revenue是一个强调句，because后是原因状语从句。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 皇家莎士比亚公司坚持说，正是这些票友给镇上带来了丰厚的收入，因为他们要在此过夜（有些人会逗留四五天），自然也就将钱大把地花在酒店和餐馆里。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　三.强调句型it was not until...that...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　强调表示时间的名词或时间状语时，常用强调句型it was not until...that...， 意为“直到……才……”。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： As was discussed before， it was not until the 19th century that the newspaper became the dominant preelectronic medium， following in the wake of the book and in the company of the periodical. (选自2002年Use of English)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是复合句，as指代it was not until the 19th century that...整个内容，分词短语following in...在句中作the news&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;paper的补足语。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 正如前面所讨论的，直到19世纪继书本、小册子的使用之后，与期刊一起，报纸成为前电子时代最重要的媒介。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： It was not until in 1971 that he was allowed to go back to his country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是复合句。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 直到1971年他才被允许返回自己的祖国。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　四.用so表示强调&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　用so强调听者同意说者所说的话，这种强调是将so提到句前，其他成分位置不变，常省略相同的部分。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： Witness payments became an issue after West was sentenced to 10 life sentences in 1995. (选自2001年Cloze Test)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 本句是一个复合句。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 自1995年韦斯特被判处10次终身监禁之后，向证人付款成为一个人们关注的问题。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　五.用wh词引导的名词从句表示强调&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： But what we forget—what our economy depends on us forgetting—is that happiness is more than pleasure without pain.（选自2006年Text 4）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是复合句，what we forget和what our economy depends on us forgetting在句中作主语。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 我们所忘记的——我们的经济希望我们忘却的是：幸福远不止是没有痛苦的快乐。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： There has to be coordination of programs. What we need is a package deal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 前句是一简单句，后句是一复合句。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 应该有一个项目上的相互协调，我们需要的是一系列的解决方案。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　六.用反身代词&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;表示强调&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： The authors of the United States Constitution themselves attempted to establish an effective national government while preserving autonomy for the states and liberty for individuals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是并列句。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 美国宪法的起草者们试图在建立一个有效的国家政府的同时，保持各州的自制权和个人自由。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　——选自《考研英语语法重难点精解（2013）》 中国人民大学出版社&lt;/p&gt;</next></skill>