<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><skill><next>&lt;p&gt;一.简单句(Simple Sentence)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　只有一个主语（或并列主语）和一个谓语（或并列谓语）构成的句子称为简单句。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： Besides generating income, the presence of other marketers makes the site seem objective, gives companies opportunities to learn valuable information about the appeal of other companies marketing, and may help expand user traffic for all companies concerned.（选自2011年Text 3）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是简单句，makes，gives和help是三个并列谓语动词。其中seem objective作宾语the site的补足语；过去分词concerned作companies的后置定语。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 除了产生效益外，这个网站由于其他营销商的参与而显得公正客观，给企业提供机会去获取其他企业成功营销策略的宝贵信息，并且可能帮助所有相关企业增大用户流量。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： Fuel scarcities and price increases prompted automobile designers to scale down the largest models and to develop completely new lines of small cars and trucks. （1999年第40题）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是简单句，主语由fuel scarcities和price increases充当，to scale down...和to develop...是两个并列宾语补足语。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 燃料短缺和价格上涨促使汽车设计师们缩小最大的型号并发展全新的小型轿车和货车的生产线。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　二.并列句(Compound Sentence)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　用等立／并列连词（或分号、冒号、逗号）把两个或两个以上的简单句连在一起构成的句子叫并列句，其中常用并列连词有and，so，not only...but also，neither/either...nor/or，or， but, still, however, while, whereas, for等。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： The supervisor didnt have time so far to go int&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;o it at length, but he gave us an idea about his plan． （1995年第38题）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是并列句，短语at length意为“详细地，详尽地”。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 主管人目前没时间对此事进行深入调查，但他对我们谈了他的打算。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： Mr. Smith had an unusual career: he was first an office clerk, then a sailor, and ended up as a school teacher． （2000年第34题）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是并列句。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 史密斯先生的职业生涯不同寻常： 刚开始是做办公室职员，然后当水手，最后做了老师。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句：Consumers passionate about a product may create “earned” media by willingly promoting it to friends and a company may leverage “owned” media by sending email alerts about products and sales to customers registered with its Web site. （选自2011年Text 3）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析：该句是由and连接的并列句，两个介词短语by willingly promoting it to friends 和by sending email alerts about products and sales to customers分别作状语，修饰谓语动词create和leverage；分词短语registered with its Web site作后置定语，修饰customers。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文：热衷于某种产品的消费者可以通过自愿推荐给朋友的方式创建“免费”媒体，而企业可以通过电子邮件把产品和销售信息发送给在其网站上注册的用户，从而充分利用“自有”媒体。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　例句： The worker and the employee are anxious, not only because they might find themselves out of a job; they are anxious also because they are unable to acquire any real satisfaction or interest in life. （选自1993年Text 2）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　分析： 该句是复合句，not only...but also...引导两个并列原因状语从句。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　　译文： 工人与雇员心情焦虑不仅仅是因为他们可能失业，而且因为他们不能在生活中获得真正的满足和兴趣。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;　&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;　——选自《考研英语语法重难点精解（2013）》 中国人民大学出版社&lt;/p&gt;</next></skill>