<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><skill><next>&lt;p&gt;目前2013考研备考正当时，英语语法中AS结构和比较结构是考研英语最常出现的语法点之一，也是考生的弱点，为了方便大家的学习，新东方在线网络课堂考研辅导团队特将考研英语语法中AS的用法及考点总结如下，希望对大家的复习有所帮助。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1、as用作固定短语&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A．as a matter of fact adv. 事实上 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm leaving for Beijing tomorrow, as a matter of fact. 实际情况是我明天就要去北京。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;B．as a whole adv. 总体上&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a whole I don’t like you, but I appreciate your life style. 总体上讲，我不喜欢你，但是我喜欢你的生活方式。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;C． as far as adv. 远到, 直到, 至于&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As far as I know, he has gone to London. 据我所知，他去了伦敦。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;就我所知，他到镇子上去了。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;D． as for 至于&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As for her family I just know that her father died when she was 8.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;E． As if 好象...似的 仿佛...一样&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She spoke to me as if she knew me. 她和我说话的神情，好像她早就认识我似的。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;F． as long &lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;as 只要, 在...的时候&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may borrow this book as long as you promise to give it back. 只要你答应归还，你就可以把这书借走。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;G． as to 关于, 至于&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't know anything as to the others. 至于其他，我一无所知。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;H． as well as adv. 也, 又&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;98年74题： If the small hot spots look as expected, that will be a triumph for yet another scientific idea, a refinement of the Big Bang called the inflationary universe theory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;词义推敲 ：&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;the small hot spots 小热点&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;refinement 更完美，提炼，改进&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;the inflationary universe theory 宇宙膨胀说(理论)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;look as expected 看上去与预计的一致”。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Triumph=victory or conquest 胜利，得胜胜利的事实，胜利或征服&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;refinement 更完美，提炼，改进&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;called：作后置定语，译作“所谓的……”，“人们称之为……”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;the inflationary universe theory 宇宙膨胀说（理论）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;参考译文：假如那些小热点看上去同预计的一致，那就意味着又一科学论说的胜利，这种论说即更完美的大爆炸论，亦称宇宙膨胀说。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2、翻译为“作为”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2005年text 4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a linguist, he acknowledges that all varieties of human language, including non-standard ones like Black English, can be powerfully expres&lt;/p&gt;</next><next>&lt;p&gt;sive—there exists no language or dialect in the world that cannot convey complex ideas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;参考译文：做为一位语言学家，他承认各种语言，包括那些非标准的语言，比如黑人英语，都具有极强的表达力——世界上任何语言或是方言都能传达复杂思想。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3，as…as …和…一样&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;99年71题：While there are almost as many definitions of history as there are historians, modern practice most closely conforms to one that sees history as the attempt to recreate and explain the significant events of the past.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;参考译文：尽管每一位历史学家都有自己对于史学的定义，现代实践最接近符合这样一个定义，这个定义把历史看作是重新创造和解释过去重要事件的尝试。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4、 not so much…as… 与其说…不如说是...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;94年71题：Science moves forward, they say, not so much through the insights of great men of genius as because of more ordinary things like improved techniques and tools.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;他们认为，科学之所以向前发展，与其说是因为天才伟人的洞察力还不如说是因为像改进了的工具和技术那些更为普通的东西。&lt;/p&gt;</next></skill>